♪ ("COLD LITTLE HEART"
BY MICHAEL KIWANUKA PLAYS) ♪
I'm trying to decide
whether I'm happy or sad.
BONNIE CARLSON: None of us
really see things as they are.
We see things as we are.
MADELEINE MACKENZIE:
This is Jane Chapman.
She's new here.
-Hi.
-Welcome!
You're... so nice.
This is Monterey.
We pound people with nice.
-(CHUCKLES)
-To death.
-(CAMERAS CLICK)
-♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
An autopsy
is still being conducted
to ascertain
the exact cause of death.
The injuries were many,
and they were severe.
We're talking
multiple broken bones.
There's clearly a lot
of bad blood in this community.
Someone hurt Amabella.
This could get ugly.
Ticking bomb.
I'll leave it at that.
You're dead in this town.
So I take it that Ziggy's father
isn't exactly a good guy.
Where is he?
No, I know
that I'll never be over it.
Something had to be wrong.
We have this... dirty secret.
When are you gonna leave him,
Celeste?
RENATA KLEIN:
I'm now one of those people
I swore I would never
turn myself into.
She can't just let us
all get along--
(YELLING) I said, "Thank you!"
You don't want anyone
getting hurt, do we?
-You threatening me?
-JANE CHAPMAN: They bully.
It's human nature.
They grow out of it.
Sometimes, they don't.
MADELEINE:
Sometimes, I'm just holding onto
this idea of perfection
so tight,
something has to give.
-(GASPS)
-(TIRES SCREECH)
(WHISPERING)
We all do bad things sometimes.
♪ (MUSIC SLOWLY INTENSIFIES) ♪
(SCREAMS)
♪ ("COLD LITTLE HEART"
BY MICHAEL KIWANUKA PLAYING) ♪
♪ Did you ever want it? ♪
♪ Did you want it bad? ♪
♪ Oh, my ♪
♪It tears me apart ♪
♪ We can try to hide it ♪
♪ It's all the same ♪
♪ I've been losing you ♪
♪ One day at a time ♪
♪ And I know ♪
♪ In my heart
In this cold heart ♪
♪ I can live or I can die ♪
♪ I believe if I just try ♪
♪ You believe in you and I ♪
♪ In you and I ♪
♪ (MUSIC ENDS) ♪
(WAVES CRASHING)
(HEART BEATING)
(BEATING SPEEDS UP)
MARY LOUISE WRIGHT:
Celeste. Celeste!
(CELESTE WRIGHT SCREAMS)
(PANTING) Oh my God.
(SIGHS) I just...
I was having a nightmare.
Oh. Shouldn't they be awake?
CELESTE: Oh my god. Oh...
Yeah. Josh. Max. Up we go.
We overslept.
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon. Let's go.
We're in a rush.
-MARY LOUISE: Come on, soldiers.
-CELESTE: Quick, quick, quick.
-Morning, Grandma.
-CELESTE: Protein bar breakfast
in the car.
(CHUCKLES) Your favorite.
MARY LOUISE: I have to go
to town. I can drop you off.
Oh... Thanks, Mary Louise.
What was it about?
Your nightmare.
Oh, it was stupid.
Nothing, really.
You said "rape."
What?
Something about a rape.
Huh.
-(FAINT BUZZING)
-(SIGHS)
Can I have some water, please?
(SNIFFLES)
(SIGHS)
-(BUZZING CONTINUES)
-(EXHALES)
♪ And I don't give a damn
About my reputation ♪
♪ ("BAD REPUTATION"
BY JOAN JETT PLAYS) ♪
♪ Never said I wanted
To improve my station ♪
♪ And I'm only doin' good
When I'm havin' fun ♪
♪ And I don't have
To please no one ♪
♪ And I don't give a damn
'Bout my bad reputation ♪
-♪ Oh, no ♪
-♪ No, no, no, no, no, no ♪
Okay, I'm putting this
in your small pocket, okay?
ZIGGY: Yep.
♪ ...My reputation ♪
-(SINGING) ♪ Reputation ♪
(YELLING) First day of school!
(SEAGULLS SQUAWK)
JOSH WRIGHT:
Stop! Hey, Max, you idiot!
Hey, hey, boys come on.
Keep it down, would you?
I can't hear myself think.
MAX WRIGHT:
Then just don't think, Mom.
-JOSH: Give it back, you idiot!
-Hey!
-Stop!
-Give it back!
MARY LOUISE: (YELLING) Hey!
Quiet!
Fine young men
don't suddenly
become fine young men
all of sudden in a whoosh,
you know.
(CLEARS THROAT)
It starts with being
fine young boys.
And part of being
a fine young boy
is listening
and respecting your mother.
She works so hard for you.
That's why the sun shines
on her so.
Thank you, Mary Louise.
MADELINE MACKENZIE:
I have two showings,
I have
Abigail's college advisor,
not to mention
all this scrutiny.
-It's just gonna be a day.
-What scrutiny?
MADELINE: Ed, this is
the first day of school.
We have to earn our
good-mom badges all over again.
"Has she gotten fatter
over the summer?
Does she look older?"
These questions get asked, Ed,
and we all get judged
all over again.
It's a complete double standard
'cause if a dad shows up,
they're like,
"Wow, there's a dad here.
He's involved."
But with the moms...
(SCOFFS)
it just makes me wanna blow.
CHLOE MACKENZIE: Boom!
MADELINE: Oh my god.
Chloe. Goddammit!
-(CROSSING GUARD BLOWS WHISTLE)
-Just right there.
I need to get right there.
-Chloe--
-(HONKS HORN)
Could you please turn it down?
Let second grade begin.
♪ ("I'LL BE AROUND"
BY THE SPINNERS PLAYS) ♪
♪ This is our bump in the road
♪ Love's last episode ♪
♪ There's nowhere to go ♪
♪ Oh no ♪
♪ You made your choice ♪
♪ Now it's up to me ♪
♪ To bow out gracefully ♪
♪ Though you hold the key ♪
♪ But, baby ♪
♪ Whenever you call me
I'll be there ♪
♪ Whenever you want me
♪ Whenever you need me
I'll be there ♪
-(BELL RINGS)
-Welcome back to our wonderful,
wonderful Otter Bay.
Gosh, I always so love
the sound of that.
Let's all say that together,
shall we?
ALL:
Wonderful, wonderful Otter Bay.
-Here we go. Now, gang...
-♪ (PIANO BEGINS JAUNTY TUNE) ♪
since we ask our children
to sing this song every year,
I think it's high time
we sing it with them,
so everybody let out
their inner otter,
and sing along.
ALL: (SINGING) ♪ Otter Bay ♪
♪ Otter Bay, it's the best plac
Of them all ♪
Very impressive. We're in
the key of F, Madeline.
ALL: (SINGING)
♪ To start our day ♪
♪ When we rise up with a snort
(SNORTING)
♪ With dance and song
And sport ♪
(SNORTING)
♪ Oh, to be a little otter
In the bay ♪
Yes! Oh, you got my otter heart
going! Thank you!
Warren. (CHUCKLES)
Really pushing the school spirit
this year, aren't you?
Well, it's my otter blood,
Madeline.
-Hi, Madeline Martha Mackenzie.
-Lisa Coolidge.
Anyway, it was
a beautiful service, Warren.
WARREN NIPPAL: (LAUGHS)
Well, thank you, Madeline,
I like to think of it more
as an assembly.
A service
is for when someone dies,
you know,
like a school fundraiser.
You're not seriously
gonna go there, are you?
My hope is that
you don't go there, Madeline.
Now, let's remember
a lot of last year's mishigas
were lovingly stirred up by you.
MELISSA:
Anybody want a red velvet?
-Melissa!
-Cupcake?
MADELINE: I'll take one
for each thigh.
MELISSA: Absolutely.
I don't even like to chew.
I just shove 'em down.
Maybe you can give one to Warren
so he can shove it too.
WARREN: (CHUCKLES)
And we're off.
-MADELINE: Bonnie.
-It's a classy crop of moms,
these ones. Those gluten-free?
MADELINE: Tahoe was good?
Uh, yeah, it was good.
Nathan caught a lot of fish.
Wow.
BONNIE CARLSON:
And I hear you're selling houses
like crazy. That's very cool.
Oh my gosh, in Monterey,
it is like printing money.
I should have done this
years ago.
-I'm gonna go find Skye.
-Okay.
Okay. Are you two fighting?
Uh, no.
Actually, I almost wish we were.
No, she's... she's been acting
like that for a while now.
Acting like what?
Shut down. Like, withdrawn.
Oh, you mean
you're not having sex.
Okay, don't forget
that Abigail has
-her college counselor meeting
at 2:00 p.m.
-Yeah, yeah, I got your--
I got your emails.
Six of them this morning.
-Good. Thank you.
-This is her future, Nathan.
Nice to be back.
I'm told that my daughter,
Amabella,
is going to be in your class.
So exciting.
Yes, very nice to meet you.
Um, she has an IQ of 152.
Genius level, right.
That's a very high number.
Life's about give and take.
I expect you to take care
of my daughter.
Pay special attention.
And, again, welcome.
Um, oh, oh, oh. (CHUCKLES)
And...
my Amabella was bullied
last year.
I mean, in like,
biting and choking.
So, we're gonna make sure
that doesn't happen again.
-(BAND PLAYS)
-RENATA KLEIN: Oh.
Oops. Sorry.
Sorry.
Here's my problem
with the whole meditation thing.
It's like you shut out
the world,
but you also shut out
your friends,
which is a little bit weird.
And also, does she look funny?
Something's not right.
-Are you talking about Bonnie?
-Uh-huh.
Like, she's off. But she was off
before she went to Tahoe.
Unplugged is one thing,
but unhinged
is a total other thing.
-(HORN BLARES)
-Hey! Asshole! Hey!
-Oh, hon.
-Why are you cutting me off?
-Honey. The horn. The horn.
-Dick! I just think we--
Oh, yeah, sorry.
Once I lean in,
you know how I am.
-CELESTE: Indeed.
-I think we need to talk to her
and see where her head is at.
-CELESTE: Do you?
-Do you want to get a coffee?
By the way, did you see Renata
getting up
that new teacher's ass?
I thought she was gonna have
to pull out her snorkel.
CELESTE: Easy. I'm gonna go
to the ladies' room;
-can you get me an Americano?
-MADELINE: Will do.
-Hey, Bruna.
-BRUNA: Hey, Madeline.
MADELINE: Wow, do you sell weed?
It smells like weed over here.
-Keep the change.
-BRUNA: Thank you so much.
-Can I get an Americano
-(DISTANT CHATTER)
and a bran muffin?
-...that's a thing?
-MADELINE: Mary Louise?
-Hi. Madeline.
-MARY LOUISE: Hi.
-Madeline!
-Yes.
-So nice to see you again.
-I'm Celeste's friend. Yes.
How have you been?
Good, good. The kids are good.
How are you?
I can't complain.
Actually, I can.
My son is dead.
But Celeste tells me that
you continue to be so helpful
with her and the boys and...
She should just get
a proper housekeeper.
-You're very short.
-(SCOFFS) Excuse me?
I don't mean it
in a negative way.
MADELINE: Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Maybe I do.
I find little people to be
untrustworthy.
(CHUCKLES) My apologies.
It's just that I'm...
I pride myself on being
a very good judge of character,
but you have always presented
such a difficult read.
You know,
you seem like a nice person.
Loving. But also,
you strike me as a wanter.
-A-- A wanter?
-Mm.
You know...
there are people in-- in life
who content themselves
with what they have,
and then there are others
who just... just want.
I'm not a wanter.
Oh, you don't have to take it
personally.
Anyway, I'm a wanter myself.
You know what I want?
I want Perry back.
I wanna know what happened
that night.
And I-- I'm very tempted
to ask you,
but I doubt I would get
the, uh...
the truth, would I?
Your son lost his balance
and he fell.
Yes, that seems to be
the company line.
Depending on whose company
you keep.
Mary Louise.
Madeline and I were just...
talking.
MADELINE:
What the hell was that?
That was a very strong position.
And I didn't like it!
Welcome to my life.
-(CARTS CRASH)
-Sorry.
Whoa. Hi!
Tori.
Sorry, I didn't recognize you
at first.
Yeah, I had my breasts done.
Oh.
Yeah, it's fabulous.
I always felt a little
self-conscious, you know.
About your breasts?
-My nose.
-Oh.
Now, nobody notices it so much.
Everybody notices these though.
And that pisses Joseph off.
So... uh...
Well, I'll see you around.
(CHUCKLES)
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY
ON LOUDSPEAKER)
DR. AMANDA REISMAN:
How long does she plan to stay?
Well, she comes and goes.
It's a short hop
from San Francisco.
She's been...
-a really big help.
-Mm-hmm.
I mean, I'd be lost without her.
So what brings you?
It's been a while.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
I've had some nightmares
starting up of late that, um...
I mean, may be triggered
by the beginning
of the school year.
I think I still...
-associate that place with...
-How could you not?
Last night was...
It was a beauty.
Perry and I were in...
the in-vitro facility, and...
it was all so sweet, and--
and suddenly, I...
I turned into a monster.
I was strangling him.
I was lifting him up, and I--
I-- (SIGHS)
It was... beyond disturbing,
and I-- I...
a little exhilarating.
Hmm...
Is that-- Do you see yourself
as a monster?
I guess I still feel...
-responsible.
-For...?
For the accident.
I mean, if I'd left him
when I should have--
We should have
never been together that night,
and he might still be alive.
That I chose that night
of all nights to leave him
and to tell him and...
Even in death,
his message lives on.
-What message?
-That you're to blame.
You're always to blame.
You're not.
-Are you getting out?
-(SCOFFS)
-Are you seeing anyone?
-No.
That part of me is still dead,
I suppose.
First thing's first: get
the boys' lives back on track,
that's the priority.
Seeing their mom happy
could help there.
So, you're saying for my life
to go on successfully,
-I need to be with a man?
-No.
But the freedom to be with one,
maybe.
You're still married, Celeste,
and the husband is dead.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
NATHAN CARLSON:
Where've you been?
I told you I was running.
That was like two hours ago,
I've been calling you.
BONNIE: Sorry.
Honey.
I just thought it might be
that you hated Tahoe,
but since we've been back...
Come on.
BONNIE: I need some space,
Nathan. I told you.
Just let it be.
JANE CHAPMAN: He's my favorite
in the whole aquarium.
It's a red octopus, and watch.
The closer he gets to the kelp,
he'll change his color
so that he camouflages
with his environment.
-CHILD: Cool.
-Look. You see him right now?
-CHILD: Yeah.
-He's changing color.
You guys want to know a fun fact
about octopus?
-ALL: Yeah!
-It's kinda weird.
-You can handle it?
-Yeah.
Okay, females contain
deadly venom,
and sometimes, they'll kill
and they'll eat the males
-after they mate with them.
-CHILDREN: (GROAN) Ew!
JANE: (CHUCKLES) I know.
SARAH: Why is it
the prettier something is,
the more dangerous?
Like with snakes and spiders.
That's a great question. I wish
I knew the answer to that.
-COREY BROCKFIELD:
One second, okay?
-You're so observant.
Sometimes, pretty colors
are to give a fair warning
so other animals know they need
to keep a safe distance.
GIRL: Oh.
There you go.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
NATHAN: How you doing?
Good. You?
Not really, no. Bonnie.
I mean, she's gone missing
in mental action.
The whole summer, truth be told.
Hey, man, could I--
could I ask you a big favor?
Could you maybe take her out
to lunch?
Um--
Listen, you've always
been better to talking to women
than I have and, you know,
you certainly got Madeline
in a way I never could.
I mean, I think you might be
able to get her to open up.
You know,
you have your little way.
All I'm getting is pushback
at every turn.
I swear to God, if I signed up
for this bullshit,
I'd still be with Maddie.
-I mean-- I don't mean--
-Oh, no, no.
Um, look, Nathan...
I'm no expert on marriage
or anything.
I mean, something tells me
if you're seeking out
the husband of your ex-wife
to, like,
lead the communication charge
with your new one...
Why do you always have to be
so snide?
-I don't mean to be snide.
-No, you don't mean to be,
it just comes natural.
It's like you're a snide fuck.
That's what you are.
You're a snide fuck.
You know, Nathan, maybe instead
of just talking to Bonnie,
you should embrace
some of her interests.
-Her interests?
-Yeah.
She won't even let me
embrace her.
-Okay.
-Yeah, you're snide.
-You're a snide fuck.
-What?
-Whatever.
-Come on.
Snide fuck.
♪ ("WHAT BECOMES
OF THE BROKENHEARTED"
BY JIMMY RUFFIN PLAYS) ♪
♪ As I walk this land
Of broken dreams ♪
(PHONE RINGING)
-♪ I have visions--  ♪ (CUTS OFF
-Hello.
-JULIETTE: (OVER PHONE)
Mrs. Klein?
-Juliette.
Hey, honey. I'm pulling in.
Can you--
-(PHONE VIBRATING)
-can-- wait.
Hold on one second. Hold on--
Hello?
MADELINE: This is why
I talk about being nice.
Hey. No, I can't--
MADELINE: What do you think?
MAN: I love the view.
Oh, sorry, I'm on the phone.
Yeah, I thought Tahoe
was supposed
to be about decompression too,
but she seems like
she's on Mars.
-Maybe she's using.
-WOMAN: Excuse me.
Yeah, just a second.
And I am beating myself up
that I told Jane
I liked her bangs.
Can you get off the phone,
please?
Hmm?
Oh, let me call you back.
♪ ("IT'S MY HOUSE"
BY DIANA ROSS PLAYS) ♪
Yeah, what can I do for you?
RENATA KLEIN:
I mean, I can't deny it.
♪ It's my house
And I live here ♪
JOEL: Good, right there.
♪ It's my house
And I live here ♪
Beautiful, come on down. Good.
Eyes up this way. Gorgeous.
I'm so tired of those shots
of women.
I mean, they're in power, right?
They own banks and they're
all, like, demure. Bullshit.
JOEL: Back to the ocean.
GORDON KLEIN: What's all this?
RENATA: Hey! The photoshoot.
Women in power.
I thought they wanted just,
uh... office shots.
No, um, they're doing house
and, uh, office.
GORDON: You look nice.
JOEL: Here we go. Look at me.
♪ And I live here ♪
(MINIATURE TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
♪ It's my house
And I live here ♪
So she has a 3.8 GPA,
and she has done charity work
with human trafficking.
She also has an internship
coming up--
Uh, Stanford has an admit rate
of under ten.
Princeton and Williams
the same,
and since she doesn't have
legacy going for her--
Any of these schools
would be lucky to have her.
-She's an excellent candidate--
-MADELINE: Candidate is,
-I think, the wrong--
-Honey.
What? Don't "honey" me.
She has a 3.8 GPA.
She has a 1350 on her SATs,
but we're gonna get
that number up
because she has private tutoring
coming up, so I feel--
I don't even want
to go to college.
(SCOFFS)
I mean, she's just--
she's just nervous.
-She doesn't mean that.
-I do mean it.
I don't want to go to college.
(CHUCKLES)
It feels so good to say that
out loud. (SIGHS)
Okay, Abigail, honey.
You're going to college.
The planet is dying, Mom,
but God forbid I don't study
Lysistrata?  It's bullshit.
Do you know what kids do
at college?
They drink. They fuck.
They mull over a sex change.
I'm not going.
All right, you're going
to college.
-I'm not going to college.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
If you wanna go, you know,
you should go.
You should go to college.
Hey, no, I know how to make
any situation about me.
This is not that.
This is about you
-and your future, Abigail.
-NATHAN: Abby.
-ABIGAIL CARLSON: I'm not going.
-I'm so sorry.
Where did she go?
I--
-Did you know about this?
-No, I swear.
You were with her all summer
in Tahoe,
and you knew nothing
about this?
-Madeline, I didn't know.
-And what about Bonnie?
Did she know about this
"fuck college" plan?
Bonnie's left the building.
Unbelievable.
You know if she doesn't go
to college,
she won't have a life.
She'll just be serving Big Macs
and French fries,
and that'll be her life.
-Is that what you want
for her, Nathan?
-Stop, stop. Stop yelling at me.
-Stop yelling at me.
-What? You know you bear
some responsibility here, right?
-NATHAN: I do?
-You're her father.
-NATHAN: Oh, okay.
-This is her senior year,
she's on the cusp of her life,
and you let it go all to shit
in Tahoe!
Don't-- You just hit me.
You just hit me.
Because you deserve it!
-(WIND RUSTLES)
-(WAVES CRASH)
But honestly, Ed,
if she doesn't go to college,
what's she gonna do?
Go into retail?
Oh, let me call you right back.
Mary Louise?
-Hey, Maddie.
-Oh, Madeline. Hello.
What's going on?
Well, I thought I might look
for a small flat here in town,
so that I could help out
with the boys
but not quite be so underfoot.
(CLEARS THROAT)
-MADELINE: Oh, I see.
-Do you work here?
-Yes.
-Do you handle rentals?
I do, actually.
Oren and I both do, yes.
I see you're wearing heels.
Yes.
Um, Oren, do you mind if I just
have a minute with Mrs. Wright?
Of course not.
You're in wonderful hands.
MADELINE: Thank you.
Mary Louise, I realize
that you're still grieving,
and that you've been through
a tremendous amount
of heartbreak,
but I don't care for the way
you spoke to me before.
It was rude,
and I didn't deserve it.
No, you didn't. Um, I apologize.
Well, thank you.
MARY LOUISE: The truth is,
it had nothing to do with you.
When I was in boarding school,
I had-- I had a best friend,
or so I thought,
who revealed herself
to be quite treacherous,
and, uh, caused me
a lot of pain.
So... she was just
an itty-bitty little thing
with a big, bubbly personality
that, um...
was designed to hide...
that she was utterly vapid
inside.
You remind me so much of her
that I suppose I punish you
for that.
That's wrong of me,
and I apologize.
-Oren.
-OREN: Yes. Sorry.
I'm sure Oren will address
all of your concerns.
MARY LOUISE: Okay.
-Where did we leave it?
-(CHUCKLES)
♪ ("MYSTERY OF LOVE"
BY SUFJAN STEVENS PLAYS) ♪
♪ Oh, to see without my eyes ♪
♪ The first time
That you kissed me ♪
♪ Boundless by the time
I cried ♪
♪ I built your walls around me
♪ White noise
What an awful sound ♪
♪ Fumbling by Rogue River ♪
♪ Feel my feet
Above the ground ♪
♪ Hand of God deliver me ♪
-♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES
THROUGH EARBUDS) ♪
-Oh!
♪ (MUSIC ENDS) ♪
(CHUCKLES) That probably
looked weird.
Yeah.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Are you on the spectrum?
-(BOTH CHUCKLE)
-Are you?
Um, I'm--
-Yeah, most likely.
-(BOTH CHUCKLE)
-Well, I don't think I am, but--
-A little advice,
you probably don't wanna act
weird and shit in public.
We do a lot of kids' events
at the aquarium,
and parents have a thing
about entrusting their kids
to psychos.
(CHUCKLES)
Noted. Got it. Thank you.
The way people talk
in this town,
I don't need to tell you.
You don't need to tell me?
What does that mean?
You're one of
the Monterey Five, right?
Monterey Five?
You were there
the night the guy fell.
Wh-- Where did you here that?
Someone at work.
I'll see you around.
Yeah.
JANE:
It was just the way he said it.
RENATA: How exactly was that?
Like we all have scarlet letters
on our backs.
-Oh, please.
-We're kidding ourselves
if we think people
have stopped talking.
Yeah, but people talk. It's--
I think we're all being
a little bit paranoid, you guys.
I think people have moved on,
and the police
definitely moved on.
-Well, we don't know for sure.
-Yeah--
No, I talked to Susie Burke.
Do you know Susie from IBM?
Yeah.
She's a good friend
of Detective Quinlan.
-Oh.
-I mean,
like, really good friend.
Gossip for another day,
but she told me that she heard
Quinlan say, like,
the case isn't "closed" closed,
but they've got nothing.
-Mm-hmm.
-CELESTE: Good.
Good.
-We're good.
-Okay.
CELESTE: Yeah, good.
(BELL RINGS)
MADELINE: Where were you?
We were waiting
for you at the beach.
Oh, yeah. Something came up.
MADELINE: Yeah?
What?
Are you all right?
-Do you care?
-Do I care?
What's going on?
I killed someone.
-Remember?
-Yes.
It's heavy.
Are you-- I mean, are you angry
at me for some reason?
I'm angry with myself.
If I had just told the truth,
I would have gotten off,
but you said he slipped,
and everyone else
joined in the fucking chorus.
-That was to protect you.
-Yeah, thanks a lot.
You know, I can't talk
to my husband.
Or my kid.
I have to just swallow it all.
You can talk to us.
We're here for you. All of us.
Well, it hasn't really felt
like that.
Well, I'm sorry,
but you've been in Tahoe.
It's not like
you can put that shit on Gmail.
-Like, what am I supposed to--
-NATHAN: Hey.
Hey. Bye, Maddie.
Little Miss Sunshine, right?
MADELINE:
Listen, I'm sorry I pushed you.
There you go, I said it.
(SIGHS) Okay, um, I need to talk
to Abby. Is she here?
NATHAN: Abby!
♪ ("THE RIP"
BY PORTISHEAD PLAYS) ♪
♪ As she walks in the room ♪
♪ Scented and tall ♪
♪ Hesitating once more ♪
-♪ And as I take-- ♪
-♪  (MUSIC ENDS) ♪
So... what was that all about?
I just don't think college
is for everyone, that's all.
MADELINE: Okay.
So why is not for you?
Well...
Starting with the cost.
It's really expensive.
So, I'm assuming
that if you're gonna abandon
that plan to go to college,
you have another plan--
I do.
What is it?
-It's to work for a startup.
-Oh, my God.
Specifically, one that builds
for-profit housing
for the homeless.
-Excuse me?
-ABIGAIL: Yeah.
And unlike, you know,
the privatized shams
like banks
and credit card companies,
ours will make money
while actually helping people.
This is something real?
I've been offered a position
to start in June.
-You cannot be serious.
-I'm gonna take it.
You cannot mortgage your future
over some sort of
short-term plan.
ABIGAIL: I'm not doing that!
Well, then, what are you doing?
There are four million
homeless people in America,
the average age
being nine years old,
-and I--
-I don't give a fuck!
I don't care
about fucking homeless people.
What?
That is not what I meant.
I do care about homeless people.
I just think you can give money
to some charity
while you actually
attend college.
-I'm not going to college.
-Yes, you are.
Give me
one good reason what I should--
It's non-negotiable.
You are going to college
because I said so,
and because you're not thinking
straight--
Because you said so?
-Yes, because I said so.
-What do you know?
You didn't go to college.
That's exactly why you're going.
Exactly.
Because you will have no life!
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SIGHS)
♪ ("THE FADE OUT LINE"
BY PHOEBE KILLDEER
AND THE SHORT STRAWS PLAYS) ♪
Can't you just tell her
it's time to go?
CELESTE: The boys love her.
I mean, they love her.
And she's... she's a big help,
she really is.
So what's up? I'm guessing
you don't need my help
on how to handle
a mother-in-law.
Why are you
not cashing the checks?
JANE: (SIGHS) I don't know.
CELESTE: Come on, Jane. Why?
It's rape money.
You know I can't do that.
Ziggy's entitled to it.
He's part of Perry's estate.
Do you ever hate me?
Just a little bit.
How could I hate you?
Because I slept
with your husband.
I mean, I didn't--
You know what I mean.
He raped you.
But I knew he was married.
I mean, I didn't know
he was married to you,
but... somebody.
No.
I don't blame you for anything.
JANE: I think I would
if I were in your shoes.
Celeste, for a man
to commit adultery,
he-- there-- there
has to be another woman,
and, you know what, more times
than not, she's complicit.
I was complicit.
Not in the end, but...
definitely in the beginning.
Are you glad that he's dead?
CELESTE: It's complicated.
(SIGHS)
(GATE BUZZES)
♪ ("HARVEST MOON"
BY CASSANDRA WILSON PLAYS) ♪
♪ Come a little bit closer ♪
♪ Hear what I have to say ♪
♪ Just like children sleeping ♪
♪ We could dream
This night away ♪
♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES
IN BACKGROUND)
♪ (JOSH PLAYS
DISCORDANT NOTES) ♪
♪ But there's a full moon
Rising ♪
♪ Let's go dancing
In the light... ♪
MARY LOUISE: Come on, everybody.
Put it away, Max.
Come.
This looks so delicious.
Thank you, Mary Louise.
MAX:
I thought we were having KFC.
Well, one cannot survive
on fast food every night.
(CHUCKLING)
We don't have it every night.
MARY LOUISE:
You know that they--
they ban these
insidious fast food institutions
from some parts
of San Francisco.
Do you remember when we walked
across the Golden Gate Bridge?
It's red.
(CHUCKLES)
You're right, it is red.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, and Dad said he was going
to swim to Alcatraz.
(LAUGHS) Oh, yeah.
Sharks would have
eaten him, stupid.
No, they wouldn't, idiot.
(SCOFFS)
-CELESTE: Hey! Hey!
-Ow!
You could hurt him!
What's wrong with you?
I barely touched him.
You stuck him with a fork, Josh.
That is unacceptable.
For God's sake.
♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES QUIETLY) ♪
I miss Dad.
I know, baby. I know you do.
We all do.
We've still got some recovery
ahead of us.
Well, they're grieving, Celeste.
Their father's death is not...
(CLEARS THROAT)
something to be recovered
from like a cold.
You know, your daddy
was the most amazing man,
and you were so lucky
to have him.
And it's very unfair and wrong
that he died.
And you still feel angry
about it, don't you?
I mean, you feel angry that
the other kids have their dads.
You don't.
You know, the other day,
I was with some friends,
and, um, their sons
were not a patch on your dad.
(LAUGHS) Not a patch.
Just-- I felt so angry.
(YELLING) Angry!
(QUIETLY) You know,
that their mediocre,
spindly, pudgy, balding,
middle-management sons--
still alive--
and my Perry...
(WHISPERING) My Perry...
I just-- felt just--
I wanted to scream.
So you know what I did?
-MAX: What?
-I did scream.
Wanna hear?
MARY LOUISE: (CHUCKLES) Okay.
(SCREAMS)
Oh!
Oh! Mary Louise! Mary Louise!
Mary Louise, please.
What, my grief is too loud
for you?
-Oh, Celeste.
-Just-- Just-- The boys!
MARY LOUISE:
I should be more discrete.
We should scream.
We should scream
and beat our breasts
and-- and tear our hair.
Don't you feel angry?
N--
MARY LOUISE: You don't?
I'm sorry.
(SIGHS)
(SOBS) I feel so, so alone.
(CLEARS THROAT)
♪ ("ALL APOLOGIES"
COVER VERSION
BY SINÉAD O'CONNOR PLAYS) ♪
♪ In the sun
I feel as one ♪
♪ In the sun ♪
♪ I'm married ♪
♪ Married ♪
♪ Buried ♪
(DISTANT WALKIE-TALKIE CHATTER)
We were like animals.
We-- We had to save her.
We-- It was like every instinct
inside of me
told me that she was--
he was gonna kill her
if we didn't help her.
And, um...
I thought he was gonna crush
her or kick her ribs in or...
I didn't know
what he was gonna do.
And then, he-- Renata or... me,
we grabbed him, and then, um...
then he grabbed Jane
by the neck.
Yeah, um....
(SNIFFS, SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
(SIGHS)
In your own time...
take a good look.
♪ (SINISTER MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
(YELLS) No!
Fucking kill you!
No!
-(PANTING)
-MARY LOUISE: Are you all right?
Celeste?
You all right?
You all right, dear?
-Yeah.
-Another nightmare?
Yes?
-It's all right.
-(SIGHS)
MARY LOUISE: It's all right.
-CELESTE: I'm sorry.
-It's all right.
So...
who are we planning to kill?
♪ ("THE FADE OUT LINE"
BY PHOEBE KILLDEER
AND THE SHORT STRAWS PLAYS) ♪
♪ It's everywhere I look ♪
♪ From Las Vegas to right here
♪ Under your dresser
Right by your ear ♪
♪ It's creeping in sweetly
It's definitely here ♪
♪ There's nothing more deadly
Than slow growing fear ♪
♪ Life was full and fruitful an
You could a take a real bite ♪
♪ The juice pouring
Well over you ♪
♪ Skin's delight ♪
♪ But the shadow it grows
And takes the depth away ♪
♪ Leaving broken down pieces
To this priceless ballet ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ Did we build
All those bridges ♪
♪ To watch them thin down
To dust? ♪
♪ Or blow them voluntarily
Out of constant trust ♪
♪ The clock is ticking
Its last couple of tocks ♪
♪ And there won't be a party
With weathering frocks ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ Heading deep down ♪
♪ We're sliding
Without noticing  ♪
♪ Our own decline ♪
♪ Heading deep down ♪
♪ We're hanging onto
Sweet nothings left behind ♪
♪ Deeper down ♪
♪ We're all going down ♪
♪ Down, deeper down, yeah ♪
♪ We are all plunging straight
Towards our own decline ♪
♪ Without noticing we slide dow
Deeper down ♪
♪ The shadow grows
Without ever slowing down ♪
♪ We are heading straight
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line ♪
♪ The shallower it grows
The shallower it grows ♪
♪ The fainter we go
Into the fade out line... ♪